Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 36.
And this exercise, we were asked to write a program to add to mystery cases.
So let's revise some basics of the addition of two mattresses of the same size.
Here we have two matrices is three eight four six plus four zero one nine minus nine.
We add the.
Elements at the same URL at the same column with the same row and same column, and we at it, we get
the result and stored them in a result of Matrix.
OK, so addition of two mattresses, this will result in a matrix.
OK, so we start by.
So we add the first element the elements of the same cell with the same position.
We add them to get a result of three plus four equal to seven.
So we store it inside matrix in the same cell in the same position.
So eight plus zero eight.
So it will result in the second column and the first through here we have in the second row the first
column for second row and the first column one four plus one is equal to five.
So we have five and six minute plus minus nine.
It will result in minus three.
So this is how we add that to mattresses of the same size.
How to implement this encoding.
And this exercise is as good.
In an Amazon interview, he told the interviewer tells that the candidate to make a program an algorithm
that add two matrices.
It's very simple, but how to implement it in the code.
First of all, we need to detect the number of rows and number of God.
So the first step?
Remember, in order to download all the source code that the code, please watch the video about the
resources and how to download it from the resources folder inside our Udemy courses.
OK, so on every on every video, there is a resource folder and the enemy, of course, is to download
its its corresponding resource quoting source code and C and D.
OK.
I am creating these variables now.
I need this cannot allow the user to enter
there at these values.
OK, I implemented the package import Java digital scanner.
System Dot and OK.
System that out, the Brent Allen input
number of rows or peas, no frills.
An equal number of and entered next and
OK system, now we need to get number of columns, so system that our footprint L and number of columns,
no
number of columns.
And equal to I and next and OK, how this is how to gather the information about the mattresses.
OK, now I am here, the first step creating mattresses.
Also, we need to continue with this step by making an array one of the array, so the Matrix is two
dimensional array and we have learned about that and that doubly or two dimensional array.
OK, so array to having these equal to you and of em and that and these are the dimension.
And OK, now the resulting array is called sum or a result result, or some some of thirties.
It's also a two dimensional array, new and array of m and balls.
OK.
This is the first step of creating these these elements.
OK, now step number two.
We need do to allow the user to enter the numbers inside the Matrix, so filling the first matrix,
how to fill it.
We start by.
We tell the user the system that ab the two.
And please enter enter first matrix.
We start by a for loop starting from C equal to zero.
This is the the element that we have created c less than the number of rows and C plus plus.
In order to fill it to the other 2D array, we need another loop.
So the equal to zero in nested loop.
So when working with when working with through the array.
Think about the nested looks like and searching, meeting and searching or whatever you want.
So this exercise is we are practicing the insertion of of elements inside to the me.
OK.
And what next?
And this is the first.
That's step number three.
Filling the second matrix the same way.
I will copy this copy and paste system and spring second.
And their second element, see what 2:00am C++ D four, two zero D of the same concept.
OK.
We are filling the second.
But here is the array number two.
OK.
This is the trick.
Now we need to make the summation, OK?
We need to start the submission.
Step number three, four step number four is telling us to make that addition.
OK, how to make additions.
We start also by looping through the and inserting inside the inside the sum.
This is the sum out of an array two dimensional array.
We need to start inserting inside the some the elements that are resulting from the addition of elements
of Array one and array two of the same position.
Inside some, this is the algorithm.
OK.
Don't worry if you don't understand we are working with you.
Step by step.
So see equal to zero start by sequence zero see less than in the same concept and the same dimensional
C++.
Now we need for the equal to zero, the less then and the plus plus gain.
Now, the sum at the end of the same and you see, guys, this is the algorithm C and D that call them
the same column and the same row of the first element and the second element.
Here we are, adding array one at Index C and an Index D of gay plus array to array two of C and D.
OK.
We are just adding that elements of the same position.
You see guys, the Index C and Index D and RF array one and element of Array two at the index and Index
D, so consider C equal to one and the equal to two.
We are adding C one and C two and we are putting inside this one and two.
I am telling that the element of the resulting array at a throw one column two is equal to the element
of the summation of elements of array, one column row, a throw one and column two, and an element
of array two of row one and column two.
So the resulting addition will be stored in the same position of row one and row to and column.
OK.
This is would be made every time we have C and D and that dimension.
So if we have inserted like three by three, so we would make this addition nine times, OK, if we
have two by two, it will result in four times four iteration of this loop.
OK.
No
system that out, that print, we need to print some of the metrics we are going to display the result
of the mattresses.
In order to print the metrics, we need step number five printing to the.
This exercise will we have learned about and we have practiced about like making conditions, storing
inside today, inserting elements and printing the results and so on.
So this is this exercise covers many, many important topics.
So see, less than M C is plus plus in the same way.
So for the equal to zero.
The same concept as above K.
Same concept.
We are just printing them out of print and print, some at index see and Index B OK.
We are printing business.
A. OK.
After we finish from this loop.
Lou?
OK.
We are going to put it every time on another line system that our print.
Ellen Mueller, gay.
Now, let's start.
Examining this program.
No afros.
OK.
We will insert three, eight, four six.
So.
The number of rows is through number of columns is two.
The first matrix is three.
Eight, four, six.
And the second matrix, four zero one minus nine, four, sorry, four zero.
Sir, you.
One minus nine.
The some of the metrics, as in metrics, seven, eight, five minus three.
Let's see.
Seven, eight, five minus three.
OK, so we are making this program works by preventing by.
Showing here I read some of the mother's print alarm system, the Delta brand and everything working
fine.
And here we go.
We have done everything clearly and we have and we have discussed many topics about that to the arrays
and like feeling like inserting the elements inside to the area, making the addition between two dimensional
array.
And we have printing that to the editor.
OK, so it's very simple.